rcu.org 2015-03-16

# 

PRIVACY POLICY
  FACTS
                                WHAT DOES ROYAL CREDIT UNION
                                DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
                                Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law
                                gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us
      Why?                      to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this
                                notice carefully to understand what we do.
                                The types of personal information we collect and share depends on the product or
                                service you have with us. This information can include:
                                    s 3OCIAL 3ECURITY NUMBER ADDRESS NAME AND INCOME
     What?                          s !CCOUNT BALANCE AND TRANSACTION HISTORY
                                    s #REDIT HISTORY AND CREDIT SCORES
                                When you are no longer our Member, we continue to share your information as
                                described in this notice.
                                All ﬁnancial companies need to share members’ personal information to run their
                                everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons ﬁnancial companies can
      How?                      share their members’ personal information; the reasons Royal Credit Union chooses to
                                share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
      Reasons we can share your personal information                   Does Share?         Can you limit this sharing?
  For our everyday business purposes—
  Such as to process your transactions, maintain your
                                                                            Yes                         No
  account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations,
  or report to credit bureaus
  For our marketing purposes—
                                                                            Yes                         No
  To offer our products and services to you
  For joint marketing with other ﬁnancial companies                         Yes                         No
  For our afﬁliates’ everyday business purposes—
                                                                            Yes                         No
  Information about your transactions and experiences
  For our afﬁliates’ everyday business purposes—
                                                                            No                    We don’t share
  Information about your creditworthiness
  For nonafﬁliates to market to you                                         No                    We don’t share
                         Call 800-341-9911 or 715-833-8111; send us an email at member_services@rcu.org or write
 Questions               to us at: Royal Credit Union, PO Box 970, Eau Claire, WI 54702-0970
                                                                 8

PRIVACY POLICY (CONT.)
 What we do
   How does Royal Credit Union         To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and
   protect my personal information?    use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These
                                       measures include computer safeguards and secured ﬁles and buildings.
   How does Royal Credit Union collect We collect your personal information, for example, when you
   my personal information?
                                       s    /PEN AN ACCOUNT OR APPLY FOR LOAN
                                       s    !PPLY FOR ANY CREDIT UNION SERVICE
                                       s    9OU VISIT OUR WEBSITE PROVIDE US INFORMATION ON ANY ONLINE
                                            application or transaction, or information you send to us by email.
                                       s    5SE YOUR CREDIT OR DEBIT CARD OR PAY YOUR BILLS
                                       s    -AKE DEPOSITS TO OR WITHDRAWAL FROM YOUR ACCOUNTS
                                       We also collect your personal information from others, including credit
                                       bureaus or other companies.
                                       Federal law gives you the right to limit only
   Why can’t I limit all sharing?
                                       s    3HARING FOR AFlLIATES EVERYDAY BUSINESS PURPOSESINFORMATION
                                            about your creditworthiness
                                       s    !FlLIATES FROM USING YOUR INFORMATION TO MARKET TO YOU
                                       s    3HARING FOR NONAFlLIATES TO MARKET TO YOU
                                       State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to
                                       limit sharing.
 Deﬁnitions
   Afﬁliates                           Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                       ﬁnancial and nonﬁnancial companies.
                                       s    .ONE
   Nonafﬁliates                        Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                       ﬁnancial and nonﬁnancial companies.
                                       s    2OYAL #REDIT 5NION DOES NOT SHARE WITH NONAFlLIATES SO THEY CAN
                                            market to you, except for our joint marketing arrangements.
    Joint Marketing
                                       A formal agreement between nonafﬁliated ﬁnancial companies that
                                       together market ﬁnancial products or services to you.
                                       s    /UR JOINT MARKETING PARTNERS INCLUDE lNANCIAL SERVICE PROVIDERS
                                                    9
